The Travel Demand Management Calculator
provides a catalog of strategies that can
be adapted
to reduce vehicle miles traveled.
Before getting started, review the What
You'll Need section for strategies of
interest to
ensure you have all necessary information.
To begin, select one or more traffic
analysis zones corresponding to the
geography of your
project.
Then, choose one or more strategies to
model.
Find relevant strategies by filtering
based on category, tag, or keyword.
We'll begin by configuring the
employer-provided commute benefits.
Let's assume that each transit trip costs
$3 and that 50% of area employers
participate
in the program.
Next, we'll configure the workplace
parking pricing.
Let's assume that workplace pricing
increases to $12 per day.
After adding to the cart, click View
Results to be taken to the results screen
to see the
impact of these strategies.
You can download a CSV with full
calculations and underlying data, or
export a PDF to share.
For more details, see the attached user
guide.